Hi, my name is Caroline and this is Amanda, we're here at Encore Gymnastics and we're going to teach you how to do a front flip.
We're going to start by stretching, so go ahead and stretch your ankles, right and left.
Turn around in a couple circles on each leg.
Very good.
You're also going to want to stretch your hamstrings, so she's going to stand up and grab the back of her foot and push this forward.
A good way to make this stretch work is by squeezing your bottom and the other leg.
There's a lot of stress on your legs when you land a front tuck because there's so much momentum in it.
And you always want to stretch your wrists and your neck as well.
Very good.
For starting a front tuck you're going to punch off the ground, so she's going to take a few steps and then just punch straight up.
The next step we would do that same exact thing but she's going to punch up and pull her knees into her stomach, so into a tuck position, same thing, pull your knees in this time.
Very good.
So we're going to have three body positions, the first one is going to be going up in the straight body, the second one is over into the tuck, and the third one is again with the bent knees, both bent knees landing, landing.
Very good, right there, so those are the three positions your body is going to go through in the front tuck.
We're going to go ahead and bring her up onto the block to show you all the way through.
You're going to start up and big jump, finish on the other side, very good.
We're going to have her do that all on her own.
She's not quite landing it because she's leaning a little bit forward, so when you do your front tuck you're going to want to go up a little bit more, go ahead and do one more for us.
Pull it all the way around.
And there it is, that's a front tuck.